Portia K. Maultsby Collection, 1981-1986.
Indiana University Digital Library Program
- Music Industry Interviews, 1979-1989, 169 audiocassettes: analog, stereo + documentation
  - 1. Interviews by Maultsby, 1979-1989, 138 audiocassettes (9,106 minutes): analog, stereo + documentation
    - Rifkind, Roy, 1986 August 17[?], INT 63; cass 1342; 1 audiocassette (19 minutes) + 1 transcript (7 typed leaves)
      Interview with Roy Rifkind, record executive for Spring Records; recorded in Atlanta, Georgia.
      Date of interview is announced as August 17, 1986, but accompanying documentation indicates as August 16, 1986.
      Compact disc(s): CDREF 199
    - Roberts, Virgil, 1983 May 19, INT 38; cass 1303; 1 audiocassette (59 minutes) + 1 transcript (23 typed leaves)
      Interview with Virgil Roberts, record executive and attorney for Solar Records; recorded in Los Angeles, California.
      Compact disc(s): CDREF 140
    - Roebuck, Richard, undated, INT 39; cass 1304; 1 audiocassette (92 minutes) + 1 transcript (43 typed leaves)
      Interview with Richard Roebuck, songwriter for Philadelphia International Records (PIR); recorded in Philadelphia, Pennsylvania.
      Compact disc(s): CDREF 141--CDREF 142
    - Russell, Albert "Diz," 1984 September 27, INT 40A--INT 40C; cass 1305--cass 1307; 3 audiocassettes (235 minutes) + 1 transcript (149 typed leaves)
      Interview with Albert "Diz" Russell, singer for the Orioles vocal group; recorded in Washington, DC.
      Compact disc(s): CDREF 143--CDREF 147
    - Sanjek, Russell, 1984 May 12, INT 98A--INT 98B; cass 1383--cass 1384; 2 audiocassettes
      Interview with Russell Sanjek, vice president for Broadcast Music, Inc. (BMI); recorded in Las Vegas, Nevada.
    - Shaw, Larry, 1984 September 5, INT 76; cass 1356; cass 1321 (copy); 1 audiocassette (36 minutes) + 1 transcript (8 typed leaves)
      Interview with Larry Shaw, president of Shaw Group, Inc. and former vice president of advertising, communications, and films for Stax Records; recorded in Memphis, Tennessee.
      Cass 1321, side A, is duplicate of cass 1356, side A.
      Compact disc(s): CDREF 209; CDREF 168 (dup)
    - Silverman, Tom, 1984 September 22, INT 41; cass 1308; 1 audiocassette (63 minutes) + 1 transcript (46 typed leaves)
      Interview with Tom Silverman, record executive for Tommy Boy Records; recorded in Washington, DC.
      Compact disc(s): CDREF 148--CDREF 149
    - Simms, Winki, 1983 January 27, INT 42A--INT 42B; cass 1309--cass 1310; 2 audiocassettes (126 minutes) + 1 transcript (33 typed leaves)
      Interview with Winki Simms, managing editor and public relations for Jack the Rapper news publication; recorded in Orlando, Florida.
      Compact disc(s): CDREF 150--CDREF 151
    - Sims, August, 1984 September 24, INT 68; cass 1348; 1 audiocassette (55 minutes)
      Interview with August Simms, artist management for Jackie Wilson; recorded in Washington, DC.
      Compact disc(s): CDREF 207
    - Smith, Frankie, 1982 December 17, INT 43; cass 1311; 1 audiocassette (40 minutes) + 1 transcript (11 typed leaves)
      Interview with Frankie Smith, songwriter; recorded in Philadelphia, Pennsylvania.
      Compact disc(s): CDREF 152
    - Smith, John, 1983 April 13, INT 44A--INT 44B; cass 1312--cass 1313; 2 audiocassettes (183 minutes) + 1 transcript (100 typed leaves)
      Interview with John Smith, record executive for Stax Records; recorded in Los Angeles, California.
      Pagination for transcript includes page 21 twice.
      Compact disc(s): CDREF 153--CDREF 156
    - Stevenson, Mickey, 1983 April 20, INT 45; cass 1314; 1 audiocassette (53 minutes) + 1 transcript (19 typed leaves)
      Interview with Mickey Stevenson, former producer and songwriter for Motown Records; recorded in Los Angeles, California.
      Pagination for transcript includes page 5 and page 14 twice.
      Compact disc(s): CDREF 157
    - Stone, J. B., 1983 May 13, INT 46; cass 1315; 1 audiocassette (69 minutes) + 1 transcript (26 typed leaves)
      Interview with J.B. Stone, program director for KJLH Radio; recorded in Los Angeles, California.
      Pagination for transcript skips page 12.
      Compact disc(s): CDREF 158
    - Stone, Jesse, 1982 November 30, INT 47A--INT 47B; cass 1316--cass 1317; 2 audiocassettes (172 minutes) + 1 transcript (53 typed leaves) and supplementary materials
      Interview with Jesse Stone, songwriter and arranger for Atlantic Records; recorded in Jamaica, New York.
      Supplementary materials consist of a press kit with biography, publicity, and news clippings, plus the following article: Santich, Kate. 2 Feb. 1992. "And the Beat Goes On." Florida Magazine: 8-13.
      Compact disc(s): CDREF 159--CDREF 162
    - Taylor, LeBaron, 1982 July 26, INT 48; cass 1318; 1 audiocassette (75 minutes) + 1 transcript (33 typed leaves)
      Interview with LeBaron, Taylor, record executive for CBS Records; recorded in New York, New York.
      Compact disc(s): CDREF 163--CDREF 164
    - Thomas, Carla, 1984 September 5, INT 9D; INT49A--INT 49B; cass 1319--cass 1320; 2 audiocassettes (136 minutes) + 1 transcript (97 typed leaves)
      Interview with Carla Thomas, songwriter and vocalist for Stax Records; recorded in Memphis, Tennessee.
      Compact disc(s): CDREF 165--CDREF 167; CDREF 64--CDREF 65 (copy)
    - Thomas, Luella, 1983 March 10, INT 85A--INT 85B; cass 1365--cass 1366; 2 audiocassettes (109 minutes) + 1 transcript (36 typed leaves)
      Interview with Luella Thomas, A&R representative for Capitol Records; recorded in Chicago, Illinois.
      Compact disc(s): CDREF 222--CDREF 224
    - Thomas, Rufus, 1984 September 6, INT 50C; cass 1321; cass 1323 (copy); 1 audiocassette (81 minutes) + 1 transcript (35 typed leaves) and supplementary materials
      Interview with Rufus Thomas, disc jockey, songwriter, vocalist for Stax Records; recorded in Memphis, Tennessee.
      Supplementary materials consist of photocopies of news clippings.
      Cass 1323, side A, is a duplicate of cass 1321; pagination for interview transcript skips page 28.
      Compact disc(s): CDREF 170--CDREF 171; CDREF 169 (copy)
    - Todd, David, 1982 December 6, INT 51A--INT 51B; cass 1324--cass 1325; 2 audiocassettes (115 minutes) + 1 transcript (40 typed leaves)
      Interview with David Todd, club disc jockey; recorded in Philadelphia, Pennsylvania.
      Pagination for interview transcript skips page 15.
      Compact disc(s): CDREF 172--CDREF 174
    - Toussaint, Allen, 1985 May 14, INT 52; cass 1326; 1 audiocassette (62 minutes) + 1 transcript (32 typed leaves) and supplementary materials
      Interview with Allen Toussaint, producer, songwriter, and pianist; recorded in New Orleans, Louisiana.
      Supplementary materials consist of photocopy of news article and a press kit from Sea-Saint Recording Studio with Toussaint's biography and portfolio.
      Compact disc(s): CDREF 175
    - Troutman, Larry, 1984 July 12, INT 79; cass 1359; 1 audiocassette (81 minutes) + 1 transcript (33 typed leaves)
      Interview with Larry Troutman, member of Zapp and president of Larry Troutman Enterprises; recorded in Dayton, Ohio.
      Compact disc(s): CDREF 212--CDREF 213
    - Vickers, Carle, 1983 April 6, INT 53; cass 1327; 1 audiocassette (54 minutes) + 1 transcript (23 typed leaves)
      Interview with Carle Wayne Vickers, trumpet arranger for LTD; recorded in Los Angeles, California.
      Pagination for interview transcript includes page 22 twice.
      Compact disc(s): CDREF 176
    - Wallace, Melvin, 1982 December 14, INT 78; cass 1358; 1 audiocassette (57 minutes)
      Interview with Melvin Wallace, record buyer for Gola Electronic, Inc.; recorded in Philadelphia, Pennsylvania.
      Compact disc(s): CDREF 211
    - Ware, George, 1982 December 6, INT 64A--INT 64B; cass 1343--cass 1344; 2 audiocassettes (128 minutes) + 1 transcript (56 typed leaves)
      Interview with George Ware, executive director of the Black Music Association (BMA); recorded in Philadelphia, Pennsylvania.
      Compact disc(s): CDREF 200--CDREF 202
    - Waters, Julia, and Oren, Luther, and Maxine Waters, 1983 March 6, INT 67; cass 1347; 1 audiocassette (92 minutes) + 1 transcript (23 typed leaves) and supplementary materials
      Interview with Julia Waters (and Oren, Luther, and Maxine Waters), member of the Waters family background singers; recorded in Los Angeles, California.
      Supplementary materials consist of Waters' recording credits and biography.
      Compact disc(s): CDREF 205--CDREF 206
    - Westbrooks, Logan, 1983 February 26, INT 54A--INT 54B; cass 1328--cass 1329; 2 audiocassettes (124 minutes) + 1 transcript (44 typed leaves), 4 8x10 in. b&w photographs, and supplementary materials
      Interview with Logan Westbrooks, record executive for CBS Records; recorded in Los Angeles, California.
      Supplementary materials consist of publicity brochure, and news clipping.
      Compact disc(s): CDREF 177--CDREF 179
    - Westbrooks, Logan [lecture], 1983 April 19, INT 87; cass 1368; 1 audiocassette (61 minutes) + supplementary materials
      Lecture by Logan Westbrooks, record executive, on the topic of the music industry; recorded by Portia K. Maultsby at California State University, Los Angeles, California.
      Supplementary materials consist of course materials for Westbrooks' PAS 490 course, "Blacks and the Business of Music," taught at UCLA, as well as a course proposal for PAS 469, "The Black Music Industry."
      Compact disc(s): CDREF 227
    - White, Granville, 1989 July 9, INT 83; cass 1363; 1 audiocassette (92 minutes) + 1 transcript (27 typed leaves)
      Interview with Granville White, record executive for CBS Records; recorded in Chicago, Illinois.
      Compact disc(s): CDREF 218--CDREF 219
    - Wiggins, Willie, 1983 February 8, INT 94; cass 1377; 1 audiocassette (53 minutes) + 1 transcript (15 typed leaves)
      Interview with Willie Wiggins, record retailer for the Orlando Platter Shack; recorded in Orlando, Florida.
      Compact disc(s): CDREF 240
    - Williams, Deniece, 1983 April 22, INT 55; cass 1330; 1 audiocassette (71 minutes) + 1 transcript (24 typed leaves)
      Interview with Deniece Williams, producer, songwriter, and vocalist; recorded in Los Angeles, California.
      Compact disc(s): CDREF 180
    - Williams, Jean, 1983 February 25, INT 62; cass 1341; 1 audiocassette (46 minutes) + 1 transcript (13 typed leaves)
      Interview with Jean Williams, artist management and writer for Billboard magazine; recorded in Los Angeles, California.
      Compact disc(s): CDREF 197
    - Williams, Jean, 1983 April 11, INT 62; cass 1341; 1 audiocassette (40 minutes) + 1 transcript (13 typed leaves)
      Compact disc(s): CDREF 198
    - Williams, Mel, 1982 November 1, INT 56A--INT 56B; cass 1331--cass 1333; 2 audiocassettes (100 minutes) + 1 transcript (58 typed leaves)
      Interview with Mel Williams, promoter and record store owner; recorded in New York, New York.
      Accompanying documentation suggests that INT 56A--INT 56B and INT 56C (dated respectively as November 1, 1982 and November 22, 1982) are two seperate inteviews. Pagination for the transcripts, however, is continuous.
      Compact disc(s): CDREF 181--CDREF 183
    - Williams, Mel, 1982 November 22, INT 56C; cass 1333; 1 audiocassette (47 minutes) + 1 transcript (58 typed leaves)
      Compact disc(s): CDREF 183
    - Williams, Myrna, 1983 April 21, INT 95A--INT 95B; cass 1378--cass 1379; 2 audiocassettes (115 minutes) + 1 transcript (33 typed leaves)
      Interview with Myrna Williams, artist management for CBS Records; recorded in Los Angeles, California.
      Compact disc(s): CDREF 241--CDREF 243
    - Witherspoon, Jimmy, 1983 May 23, INT 57; cass 1334; 1 audiocassette (92 minutes) + 1 transcript (42 typed leaves)
      Interview with Jimmie Witherspoon, vocalist; recorded in Los Angeles, California.
      Compact disc(s): CDREF 184--CDREF 185
    - Young, Earl, 1982 November 27, INT 58A--INT 58B; cass 1335--cass 1336; 2 audiocassettes (118 minutes) + 1 transcript (43 typed leaves)
      Interview with Earl Young, drummer and producer for Philadelphia International Records (PIR); recording location unknown.
      Compact disc(s): CDREF 186--CDREF 188
  - 2. Interviews by Various Interviewers and Miscellaneous Recordings, 1979-1989, 31 audiocassette
    - Arnold, Larkin, radio interview for KACE, 1983 February 27, INT 5; cass 1240; 1 audiocassette (57 minutes); Unidentified
      Recorded radio interview with Larkin Arnold, record executive for CBS Records, on KACE radio program, "So You Want to Be…," broadcast on February 27, 1983, in Los Angeles, California.
      Compact disc(s): CDREF 51
    - Ballard, Hank, 1982 July 1, INT 72; cass 1352; 1 audiocassette; Gross, Laura
    - Bass, Ralph, 1984 April 19, INT 82; cass 1362; 1 audiocassette (89 minutes) + 1 transcript (25 typed leaves); Fox, Jon
      Interview with Ralph Bass, record executive for King/Federal Records.
      Compact disc(s): CDREF 216--CDREF 217
    - Bobettes, undated, INT 73; cass 1353; 1 audiocassette + transcript (3 typed leaves); Gross, Laura
    - Calloway, Cab, undated, INT 99; cass 1384; 1 audiocassette; Betty, Michael
    - Chantelles, undated, INT 73; cass 1353; 1 audiocassette; Gross, Laura
    - Chantels, undated, INT 75; cass 1355; 1 audiocassette + 1 transcript (4 typed leaves) and supplementary materials; Gross, Laura
      Supplementary material consists of a photocopy of the following article: Redmond, Mike and Steve West. "Arlene Smith & the Chantles." Source and date unknown.
    - Checker, Chubby, undated, INT 74; cass 1354; 1 audiocassette + 1 transcript (4 typed leaves); Gross, Laura
    - Flamingos, undated, INT 73; cass 1353; 1 audiocassette + 1 transcript (5 typed leaves); Gross, Laura
    - Francis, David "Panama," 1983 December 31, INT 16A--INT 16C; cass 1261--cass 1263; 3 audiocassettes (142 minutes) + 1 transcript (144 leaves) and supplementary materials; Hinton, Milt
      Reading by Portia K. Maultsby of a printed transcript of an interview with David "Panama" Francis conducted by Milt Hinton for the Jazz Oral History Project, supported by the National Endowment of the Arts, Smithsonian Institution; recording date and location unknown.
      Supplementary materials include correspondence between Francis and Maultsby, news clippings, photocopies of articles and promotional materials, and Maultsby's notes on Francis.
      Transcript is the original transcript for Hinton's interview and not a direct transcript of cass 1261--cass 1263. Cass 1263, side B contains a broadcast of a spotlight interview with David "Panama" Francis, on the program "Jazz at One" on WKCR radio, date and location unknown.
      Compact disc(s): CDREF 83--CDREF 85
    - Francis, David "Panama," undated, INT 16A--INT 16C; cass 1263; 1 audiocassette (28 minutes); Unidentified
      Taped broadcast of a spotlight interview with David "Panama" Francis on the program Jazz at One on WKCR radio; recording date and location unknown.
      Compact disc(s): CDREF 219
    - Hollywood Live: Lakeside, undated, MI 16; cass 1397; 1 audiocassette
    - Interviews with Various Artists: James Alexander (Bar-Kays), Grandmaster Flash, undated, MI 13; cass 1396; 1 audiocassette; Unidentified
    - Jacksons Publicity Material, undated, MI 12; cass 1395; 1 audiocassette
    - KACE Radio: Alonzo Miller, undated, MI 17; cass 1398; 1 audiocassette
    - KACE Sharan Orlen: Sex in Music, undated, MI 11; cass 1394; 1 audiocassette
    - Little Anthony, 1979 August, INT 70; cass 1350; 1 audiocassette + 1 transcript (26 typed leaves) and supplementary materials; Gross, Laura
      Supplementary material consists of the following article: Tong, Kevin. 22 May-4 Jun. 1989. "Little Anthony and the Imperials: No Tears on My Pillow." R&B Report: 19.
    - Maultsby, Portia, Recorded Research Notes, undated, [unnumbered]; cass 1276; 1 audiocassette (2 minutes)
      Reading of historical background and quoted material relating to the formation of Soul magazine.
    - Medlin, Joe, Interview at Swarthmore College, 1982 October 28, INT 61A--INT 61B; cass 1339--cass 1340; 2 audiocassettes: analog, stereo; Mason, Barbara
    - Music of Black America: Black Rock-n-Rollers, Second Generation Artists, undated, MI 2; cass 1385; 1 audiocassette
    - Music of Black America: Composers I & II, undated, MI 6; cass 1389; 1 audiocassette
    - Music of Black America: Duets I, Super Hookups, undated, MI 8; cass 1391; 1 audiocassette
    - Music of Black America: Ebony and Ivory, Instruments to Vocal, undated, MI 9; cass 1392; 1 audiocassette
    - Music of Black America: High Steppin', High Voices, undated, MI 3; cass 1386; 1 audiocassette
    - Music of Black America: Life and Music of James Jamerson, undated, MI 4; cass 1387; 1 audiocassette
    - Music of Black America: Message in the Music, in Search of the L.A. Sound, undated, MI 7; cass 1390; 1 audiocassette
    - [Panel discussion], undated, cass 1342; 1 audiocassette (48 minutes)
      Panel discussion from a record and radio industry conference, including speakers such as Kenny Gamble; recorded by Portia K. Maultsby in Atlanta, Georgia.
    - Price, Lloyd, undated, INT 71; cass 1351; 1 audiocassette + transcript (14 typed leaves); Gross, Laura
    - R&B Forum: Ain't No Stoppin' Us Now, the Future of R&B Radio, 1989 July 8, MI 18; cass 1399; 1 audiocassette
    - R&B Forum: The Foundation of a Recording Career; Artists Imaging Worldwide, 1989 July 7, MI 19; cass 1400; 1 audiocassette
    - Rhythm Talk [performed by] Douglas "Jocko" Henderson, Philadelphia International, undated, MI 5; cass 1388; 1 audiocassette
      Appears to be a dub of commercial LP released by Philadelphia International.
    - Shirelles, undated, INT 75; cass 1355; 1 audiocassette + 1 transcript (15 typed leaves); Gross, Laura
    - Short Interviews with Artists: Michael Jackson, undated, MI 10; cass 1393; 1 audiocassette; Unidentified
    - Standing in the Shadows of Motown, undated, MI 4A; cass 1387; 1 audiocassette
    - Wonder, Stevie, undated, INT 59; cass 1337; 1 audiocassette; Unidentified
      Commercial broadcast of interview with Stevie Wonder, vocalist, songwriter, producer, and keyboardist.